[Music]
welcome to another episode of the usada
pitch my guest today is scott david who
is an elite education lead here on our
usada education team
scott welcome to your first episode of
the pitch how's it going today it's
going really good avery uh just a
beautiful day here in colorado springs
and there's another busy day at usada as
always
let's go oh greed so with the conclusion
of the beijing games scott is joining us
to provide a post games recap of how
usada works to ensure that athletes and
support personnel are educated prior to
major games so scott what are your main
responsibilities when it comes to major
games yeah so that's a great question
i'm primarily responsible for you know
making sure athletes and athlete support
personnel are
you know have all the education that
they need prior to going to the games
and this starts as soon as the rules
come out so once the rules come out we
read them as a team
and then we figure out
you know what initiatives and and create
educational materials uh for all usa
credentialed athletes and athletes for
personnel
and then after that i start working with
the national governing bodies and the
usopc
to identify who how and when we can
reach those uh stakeholders
awesome a lot of people a lot of
organizations involved
yes
so what are some of the education
initiatives the elite education team
implemented for the beijing winter games
yeah another great question so um with
the exception of maintaining the 24 hour
24 7 hotline i should say for the
athletes at the games usada's education
team's
role is pretty much wrapped up when the
games start respectively for paralympics
and the olympics
leading up to the games though we try to
get in front of as many sport
disciplines with face-to-face games
specific education as possible
and for these games we facilitated
several beijing specific presentations
reaching over 140 athletes and athlete
support personnel so that was really
cool to see
we also maintained tutorial compliance
reports for the usopc and on top of that
every credentialed staff and athlete did
take the required clean sport course and
athletes and athlete support personnel
took the optional course so that was
really cool that you know people were
buying into that it's a great thing for
clean sport
and then lastly you know this this
really shows how important it is team
usa
and then in collaboration with our
communications department we also
provide a webpage that's always updated
with the game specific information and
physically we sent 400 bags of education
materials to the athletes that were in
beijing so lots of things uh you know
touch points to try to get to the
athletes
that is a lot so how does the education
team know if these initiatives actually
worked well for athletes or not
yeah um and that's a question we ask
ourselves often so what we do is we
thoroughly evaluate all of our programs
not just games education and then once
the games end we will send a survey to
our stakeholders and hopefully the idea
is to better understand if we met our
goals but also position american
athletes athletes support personnel to
be informed advocates for clean sport
and ensure they receive effective
education
awesome so how does a games year impact
everything else usada's education team
needs to complete each year
it's a huge impact we're always busy as
it is so in a games year we're even more
busy let alone back-to-back uh games in
a row with tokyo and then beijing
so the way we're able to do this is by
ensuring we have solidified processes
for everything we do to run efficiently
and although i lead the games education
and i'm primarily responsible for
everything it couldn't be accomplished
without everyone on the team working as
a well-oiled machine
every member of this elite education
team plays a huge role
in the games education and the varied
skill sets amongst the team allows for
success during this time
now that the games have wrapped up
what's next on the agenda for you yeah
so once the game is wrapped up you know
we do a full debrief internally but then
we also do a debrief with the usopc just
to make sure our initiatives are in line
and how can we be better in the future
for games like parks 2024
and after that i'm really able to focus
more intensely on
you know the athlete presenter program
as well as a dco educator program
makes sense all right scott great to
hear from you thanks so much for sharing
yeah no problem avery thank you for
having me
we'll see everyone for another episode
of the pitch soon
[Music]
you